我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
-被令人难以置信的东西杀害  -快跑  巴里
- by something impossible. - Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensics scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到
And one day, I'll find
杀害母亲的凶手
who killed my mother...
让我父亲沉冤得雪
And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am...the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on the Flash...
西斯科  如果你不封锁这场爆炸
Cisco, if you don't seal off the blast,
这楼里所有人都会死  包括凯特琳
everyone in this building will die, including Caitlin.
不要再找我了
Don't look for me again.
罗尼还活着
Ronnie's alive,
他在外面孤独且恐惧地活着
and he's out there, alone and scared.
哈特利·拉瑟威的科学头脑
Hartley Rathaway Possesses one of the finest
是我见过最好的之一
scientific minds I've ever encountered.
我无法想象等你打开门
I can't imagine how you're gonna feel
放我出去之后又会作何感受
when you open up these doors and let me out of here.
我为什么要这么做
Why would I ever do that?
因为我知道罗尼·雷蒙德的下落
Because I know where Ronnie Raymond is.
亲爱的  亲爱的
Honey...honey...
丹娜  上帝啊
Dana. Oh, God.
有人吗
Someone!
-救命  -谁来救救我们
- Help! - Please help us.
看看你能不能切断那条线的电源
See if you can get the power of that line shut down.
你们去铺好水带
You guys lay down the hose line.
-帮帮我们  -救救我们
- Please help! - Help us!
救救我们
Help us!
撑住
Hold on!
呆在这  好吗
Stay here, all right?
有我呢
I gotcha.
丹娜
Dana!
你怎么...
How did--
我爱你
I love you.
谢谢你
Thank you,
闪电侠
Flash.
第一季  第十二集
老兄
Dude.
那简直太酷炫了
That was insane.
我是说
I mean,
你把我的衣服弄脏  我都很难发火了
even I'm having a hard time getting mad at you for dirtying up my suit.
什么时候那才能成为我的衣服
Okay, when are we going to start considering it my suit?
我觉得应该叫做我们的衣服
I'd be comfortable calling it our suit.
我们的衣服
Our suit.
今晚是你跑的最快的一次
Tonight was the fastest you've ever run.
是的  你的训练出成果了
Yes, your training is paying off.
那对夫妇今晚能活下来多亏了你
That couple is alive tonight because of you.
我还能更快  我知道我可以
I can still get faster. I know I can.
有一天你会的  我很确定
And you will one day, I'm sure.
但是今天
But for today,
我觉得你已经做得够好的了
I'd say you've fulfilled your save quota.
你需要睡个好觉  我们都需要
Proper rest is what you need, as do we all.
还有更好的  我们都需要喝一杯
Better yet, what we all need is a proper drink.
谁想来一杯
Who's up for a round?
老兄  我今晚得和乔看电影
Oh, dude, it's-- it's movie night with Joe.
我去不了
I can't.
明天再见  好吗
But I'll see you guys tomorrow, all right?
-再见  -晚安
- Bye. - Night.
那你呢
What about you?
我请客
Drinks on me?
我觉得还是算了吧
I think I'll pass.
你没事吧
You okay?
我在你的工作室里找我的平板
I was looking for my tablet at your work station,
然后我发现了这个
and I found this.
火风暴理论
我可以解释
I can explain.
我知道你说了不要去找罗尼
I know you said we should stop looking for Ronnie,
所以我...
so I...
就没停止寻找罗尼
didn't stop looking for Ronnie.
为什么
Why?
哈特利  他说他知道罗尼发生了什么
Hartley. He said he knew what happened to Ronnie.
哈特利·拉瑟威
Oh, Hartley Rathaway,
是那个因为用声波大肆破坏
who is currently locked up in our super-villain basement jail
而被锁在咱们关超级恶棍的牢房中的家伙吗
for going psycho with sound waves?
是  他做了一些错误的决定
Yeah. He's made some poor choices.
这毋庸置疑
There's no argument there.
但是我去查了一下他所说的...
But I looked into what he was saying and--
西斯科  罗尼死了
Cisco. Ronnie's gone,
现在是时候继续过我的生活了
and it's time for me to move on with my life.
看起来可不像
Doesn't seem like it.
你这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你看  我不是什么恋爱的专家
Look, I'm not an expert on love,
但我觉的你要想忘掉罗尼
but I think in order to move on from Ronnie,
就必须得释怀
you actually have to move on.
站住别动
Hold it right there!
肖娜
Shawna?
她在这里
Hey, there she is!
相当酷  对吧
Crazy cool, right?
你怎么做到的
How did you do that?
抓住我的手
Grab my hand.
怎么回事  肖娜
How the hell, Shawna?
怎样  你喜欢吗
So, you like?
我爱死了
Oh, I love.
监狱里大半的监控都被关掉了
The security cameras in half the prison are shut down.
克莱·帕克  根据这里的记录显示
Then Clay Parker, according to this data log,
他当时还被关在牢房中
who was still locked in his cell,
但不知为何消失了
somehow vanishes.
没完全消失
Not completely.
那是什么
What's that?
某种有机微粒残留
It's some kind of organic particulate residual.
我在这里的地板上找到的
I found it on the floor in here,
就在牢房外
just outside the cell,
在走廊上
out in the hallway.
痕迹一路延向牢外
Trail led me all the way outside.
爸爸
Dad.
据说  帕克越狱了
Word around here is, Parker pulled a Shawshank?
没错  而且其他犯人
Yep, and none of the other prisoners
没有听见或看见任何事
heard or saw anything.
他们是不会跟你们说的
Well, they wouldn't talk to you about it.
所以我们没什么线索
Leaves us with not a lot to go on.
如果有谁能够搞清帕克是怎么逃走的
Well, if there's anyone who can figure out how Parker got out of here,
那就是你了  儿子
it's you, son.
来吧  艾伦  我们走吧
Come on, Allen, let's go.
使命召唤
Duty calls.
我爸爸只是刚好经过吗
So, my dad just happened to come by?
狱警之前欠我个人情
The guard owed me a favor.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你
Thanks for...
把我从那个地狱救出来
getting me out of that hellhole.
换做是你也会为我做同样的事吧  对吗
You'd have done the same for me, right?
所以说
So...
你到底遭遇了什么
how the hell did this happen to you?
我也不知道
Don't know.
你被关起来之后  我开始感觉不对劲
After you got locked up, I started not feeling right.
我无缘无故地晕倒
I was passing out for no reason,
在陌生的地方醒来
waking up in odd places.
我花了一段时间才掌控这种能力
It took me a while before I could control it.
我一得心应手
Soon as I could...
就来找你了
I came for you.
所以你能就这样
What, so you can just
跑到任何想去的地方
jump wherever you want?
只要我能看见目的地
If I can see where I'm going.
我们有了全新的机会  克莱
We got a second chance, Clay.
我们可以离开中城
We can leave Central City.
之前说的那些事都可以做了
Do-do all the things we talked about.
我还不能走  宝贝
I can't leave yet, baby.
我欠马克斯很多钱
I owe Marcus a lot of money.
还债之前我逃了
I skipped town before paying him back.
他会找到我们的
He'll find us.
可是有你的能力
Hey, but with what you can do,
我们能轻松还掉这笔钱
we can pay off that debt.
然后我们就自由了  想去哪都可以
Then we'll be free, and we can go anywhere in the world.
我们一起去
Together.
巴里的细胞都活动不了这么快
Not even Barry's cells move this fast.
我从没见过这样的东西
I've never seen anything like it.
所以克莱·帕克是个超能力者
So Clay Parker is a meta-human?
没这么简单
Not so fast.
巴里在铁山监狱找到的微粒残留
The particulate residue Barry gathered
里面的确有克莱·帕克的DNA
at Iron Heights does contain Clay Parker's DNA,
但同时还有一个女人的DNA
but also DNA of a woman.
把她的DNA与中城警局的犯罪数据库进行对比
Run her DNA against the CCPD criminal database.
看看能不能找到吻合的数据
See if you get a match.
找到了
Yahtzee.
她叫肖娜·贝兹
Her name's Shawna Baez.
大部分都是小打小闹
Mostly petty crimes,
很明显这个女孩特别喜欢派对
and this girl likes to party, apparently.
中城警局犯罪数据库  肖娜·贝兹
在本地酒吧闹过很多次事
Long list of disorderly conducts at local bars.
我想只要找到她  就能找到克莱·帕克
So I'm guessing we find her, we find Clay Parker.
-巴里  -来了
- Barry? - Yeah.
我们继续追查这些微粒残留
In the meantime, let's track these particulates
看它们是怎么回事
and see how they work.
我马上就来
I'll be right with you guys.
我现在很想吃泰国菜
I've had the biggest craving for Thai food.
你说你知道罗尼遭遇了什么
You said you knew what happened to Ronnie
还知道他是怎么活下来的
and how he was still alive.
你说爆炸那晚  斯泰因教授
And you said Professor Stein was at S.T.A.R. Labs
也在尖端科研实验室
the night of the explosion.
他的确在
Yes. He was.
为什么
Why?
问题不在于斯泰因那晚为何去了尖端实验室
The mystery isn't why Stein went to S.T.A.R. Labs that night.
而是在于他为何没有离开
It's why he didn't leave.
告诉我
Tell me.
不能说  我得展示给你看
Can't. I have to show you.
我是不会放你出来的
You are not getting out of this cell.
好吧  但是我了解你  西斯科
Fair enough, but I know you, Cisco.
我知道你有多敬仰罗尼
I know how much you looked up to Ronnie.
他就像家人一样
He was like family.
你在这里给自己建立的小家庭
A family you built for yourself here.
我知道你有多想修补这个家庭的创伤
I know how much you want to see that family healed.
让我来帮你
Let me help you.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我说的可是实话  西斯科
Well, I'm telling you the truth, Cisco.
等你准备好了  你知道上哪找我
When you are ready, you know where to find me.
你笑什么
What's that smile about?
我今天看见我爸了
I saw my dad today.
没有隔着玻璃  也不是隔着电话
No glass, no phones.
只有我和他  面对面在一起
Just me and him, face-to-face.
乔安排了一切
Joe arranged it.
那肯定棒极了  巴里
That must have been amazing, Barry.
是啊  我真的很需要这个
Yeah. I really needed it.
我相信他也很需要
I'm sure he needed it, too.
你是在那调查越狱的事吗
Were you there investigating the breakout?
-没错  -那可是个大料
- Mm-hmm. - That is a big story.
可惜我没能参与其中
Which I am not a part of.
我的编辑想让我写闪电侠的事  只写闪电侠
My editor wants me writing about the Flash, and only the Flash.
这是件坏事吗
Is that a bad thing?
我不知道  我就是觉得
I don't know. I would just like
我不想只当闪电侠的公关专家
to be thought of as more than the Flash PR flack.
如果我不赶快写点什么出来
I mean, if I don't write something soon,
我想我可能要失业了
I think I might lose my job.
不会的
Hey, no.
我们会帮你找到一个很有价值的新闻的
We will find you a great story to write about.
我们一起找
Together.
好吗
Okay?
你知道我会一直支持你
You know I'm always here for you.
我知道
I know.
没想到你还挺愿意做这种交易
Didn't know you enjoyed yourself a little rough trade.
如果我放你出来
If I'm gonna let you out,
我绝不会冒任何风险
I'm not taking any chances.
好奇心简直令人发狂  不是吗
Curiosity's a maddening thing, is it not?
你说你在四处打听是什么意思
What do you mean you've been asking around?
你认识一个叫马克斯·斯德哥海默的人吗
Do you know a Marcus Stockheimer?
当然  他是个帮派中层
Sure, he's some mid-level gangster.
主要在南边活动
He works mainly on the south side.
据说  克莱·帕克之前是给马克斯跑腿的
Word is, Clay Parker was a runner for Marcus.
克莱被抓后  马克斯失去了很多钱
When Clay got pinched, Marcus lost a lot of money.
很显然  马克斯不喜欢失去钱
Apparently Marcus doesn't like losing money.
所以呢  帕克在还清债之前
So, what? So Parker can't leave Central City
不能离开中城吗
until he's paid off his debt?
据我所知
From what I'm told,
如果你是斯德哥海默的人
if you're a member of the Stockheimer crew,
你出去后
you get out,
要立刻去拜访他
first thing you do is pay him a visit
否则后果自负
or suffer the consequences.
好了
All right.
别再扮演警察了
No more playing cop.
向我保证
Promise me.
我听见了
I hear you.
好的
All right.
你说要告诉我罗尼发生了什么
You said you were gonna show me what happened to Ronnie.
可罗尼是死在楼里面
Ronnie died inside the building.
我们出来干嘛
What are we doing out here?
你看见了什么
What do you see?
不知道
I don't know.
大楼  高墙  尘土
Buildings, walls, dirt.
威尔斯一定会对你的观察力很失望
Wells would be so disappointed in your observational skills.
再看一下
Look again.
[日语]
是日语
It's Japanese.
为什么你会说六种语言
How can you speak six languages
但是每种说出来都有混球的味道
and sound like a dick in every one of them?
意思是"炸弹影子"
It means "bomb shadow"?
第一颗原子弹被扔到广岛后
They found these all over Hiroshima
人们在那里发现了很多这种影子
after the first atomic bomb was dropped.
这个影子是马丁·斯泰因的
This shadow belonged to Martin Stein.
是加速器爆炸造成的吗
The accelerator explosion did this to him?
你真的不明白  是吧
You really don't see it, do you?
等你想明白后你都会抽自己两个嘴巴
You're gonna kick yourself when you figure it out.
行了吧
Oh, man.
你以前很能扯  现在还是很能扯
You were full of it then, and you're full of it now.
这不过是你另一个拙劣的把戏
This is just another one of your lame-ass tricks.
走吧
Come on.
回管道监狱去
We're going back into the Pipeline.
不是只有你才懂振动  哈特利
You're not the only one who understands vibrations, Hartley.
你戴的人工耳蜗
Those cochlear devises you're wearing?
我做了点调整
I made a few adjustments.
不要  求你了
No, please don't!
如果你知道怎么找到罗尼
If you know how to find Ronnie,
你最好告诉我
then you better tell me.
立刻
Right now.
求你了  让它停下
Please, make it stop.
求你了  我给你看
Please. I'll show you.
我给...
I'll show...
你再敢这样
Try that again,
我就不会停下了
and I won't make it stop.
永远不会
Ever.
真让我印象深刻
I'm impressed.
我还以为你没这胆量
Didn't think you had that in you.
不过你得把这些解开
But you have to take these off me
如果你想知道真相的话
if you want to find out the truth.
为什么
And why's that?
这东西在我们要去的地方太引人瞩目了
It'll look a little conspicuous where we're going next.
我之前在分析
I was analyzing the particulates
克莱·帕克和肖娜·贝兹留下的粒子
that Clay Parker and Shawna Baez left behind,
我发现了很有意思的事情
and I found something very interesting.
当克莱的细胞跟肖娜的细胞接触时
When Clay's cells come into contact with Shawna's,
就会吸收她的特质
they adopt her properties.
你有什么心事吗
Something bothering you?
为什么这么问
Why would you ask that?
你在咬自己的下嘴唇
You're doing that biting-your-lower-lip thing
一般你有心事时会这样
that you do when something's bothering you.
我没事
I'm fine.
好吧
Okay.
西斯科说我没有自己的生活
Cisco says I don't have a life.
你没有  对吧
You don't, do you?
我有
I do!
我做饭  然后吃掉
I cook and I eat
我还读书
and I read
还协助你
and I help you.
也就是说  你做的都是些
So, what you're saying is, you do everything
没有生活乐趣的事
that has nothing to do with having a life.
你没必要这么不友好
You don't have to be rude about it.
我比你也好不到哪去
Hey, I'm not doing any better than you.
我的社交生活就是
My social life consists of
飞速地奔跑和在网上看剧
running at superhuman speed and Netflix.
咱俩可真是一对  艾伦先生
We are quite the pair, Mr. Allen.
是的没错  斯诺博士
Yes we are, Dr. Snow.
有一起正在进行的持枪抢劫
There's an armed robbery in progress.
两个嫌犯  一男一女  二十多岁
Two suspects, male and female in their 20s.
貌似我们的超能力雌雄大盗
Sounds like our meta-human Bonnie and Clyde
又在犯案了
are at it again.
该去破坏他们的社交生活了
Time to ruin their social life.
再来几包  宝贝  马克斯的份就够了
Just a few bags, baby, is enough to pay back Marcus.
这东西比看上去沉多了
These things are heavier than they look.
我看过你的新闻
Oh, I've read about you.
你就是闪电侠
You're the Flash.
我听说你速度很快
I've heard you're real fast.
来验证一下吧
Let's see if it's true.
你能抓住我吗
Catch me if you can.
我能
I can.
你跟我开玩笑呢吧
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
没几个男人能追上我
Not too many men can keep up with me.
这是枪伤
This is a bullet wound.
你该庆幸只是擦破了皮
You're lucky it just barely broke the skin.
看来我比高速子弹快多了
Guess I'm a lot faster than a speeding bullet.
肖娜·贝兹
Shawna Baez.
她可以瞬移
She can teleport.
是那个"传送我吧  肖娜"吗
As in,"Beam me up, Shawna"?
是的  当然
Yes, of course.
量子缠绕
Quantum entanglement.
可以在一定距离内操控
The ability to manipulate interconnected particles
互相联系的粒子的能力
over an infinite distance.
或者  用爱因斯坦的说法
Or, as Einstein put it,
"唬人的超距作用"
"spooky action at a distance".
每次我一靠近  她就消失了
Every time I got close, she'd disappear.
就像我们在玩...
It was like we were playing a game of--
躲猫猫
Peek-a-boo.
怎么  我不能起一次名字吗
Come on. Can't I name one?
这要我怎么抓住她
How am I supposed to catch her,
我连她会在哪儿出现都不知道
if I don't know where she's gonna be?
每个人都有局限性  艾伦先生
Everybody has limits, Mr. Allen.
现在我们知道了肖娜的超能力
Now that we know Shawna's powers,
就可以集中精力发掘她的局限
we'll focus on those limits.
好吧
All right.
有进展告诉我一声
Let me know.
我要去换衣服了
I'm gonna change.
我得去帮爱瑞丝
I gotta go help Iris.
嗨  巴里
Hey, Barry.
-嗨  艾迪  -嗨  你在这儿干什么
- Hey, Eddie. - Hey, what are you doing here?
我来看看你给报社写的故事
I thought I'd see if you wanted help
是否需要帮忙
writing your story for the paper.
这真贴心  我很愿意
Oh, that is so sweet. I would love to,
但我们今晚要和艾迪的妈妈共进晚餐
but we were about to have dinner with Eddie's mom tonight.
而且我们已经迟了
And we're late.
我们能下次再约吗
Can we do it another time?
嗯 好啊
Yeah, yeah...yeah.
好的
Okay.
-那就这样  -拜
- All right. - Bye.
-再见  -拜
- See ya. - Bye.
肖娜和克莱是哪些酒吧的常客
What bars did Shawna and Clay frequent?
大多是城南的私人酒吧
Uh, mostly south side dive bars.
问这个干嘛
Why?
我想去调查一下
I was just gonna check 'em out.
看看他们有没有重染旧习
See if they fall into any old habits.
好想法
That's a good idea.
我和你一起去
I'll join you.
每个人都在猜想
"Everyone's wondering."
今夜你是否会来
"Will you come out tonight?"
每个人都想做好
"Everyone's trying to get it right."
拨云见日
"Get it right."
怎么了
What?
没什么
What? Nothing.
唔  你看起来
Uh, well, you look...
很棒
really nice.
我不总是打扮得像个高中校长的
I don't always dress like a high school principal.
所以  这里就是
So, this is where
肖娜·贝兹和克莱·派克以前常来的地方
Shawna Baez and Clay Parker used to hang out?
是啊  根据资料上是的
It is, according to the files.
我觉得我们可以一石二鸟
I thought we could kill two birds with one stone.
在找他们的同时  我们也能回归生活
Look for them and get ourselves back out there.
我一直在犯同一个错误
I keep making the same mistake.
每一次爱瑞丝陷入困难  我都冲过去救她
Every time Iris falls, I race to pick her up,
想着也许有那么一次情况会有所改变
thinking that one of these times things are gonna change,
但情况永远都不会改变
but I...things are never gonna change.
我注定永远只是个朋友
I am just destined to be just the friend.
至少你爱上的人不会浑身起火
At least you're not pining for someone who bursts into flames
还不想和你有任何瓜葛
and wants nothing to do with you.
我们到底怎么了
What is wrong with us?
我们才二十多岁
I mean, we're in our 20s.
我们应该尽情享乐
We should be having fun.
我们应该认识不同的人
We should meet people,
疯狂约会
go on lots of dates.
好  酒壮怂人胆
Well, here's to liquid courage.
哇  你喝得真猛
Uh...that is...very fast.
全喝光了
Drank all of it.
你好
Excuse me?
能记我账上吗
I would like to start a tab.
中城警局在爆炸之后收缴了尖端科研实验室的
CCPD confiscated everything from S.T.A.R. Labs
所有资料
after the explosion.
录影资料  录音资料  交通摄像
Video, audio, traffic cam footage.
所以呢
Okay, so?
我在尖端科研实验室被炸的那晚看到了马丁·斯泰因
I saw Martin Stein the night S.T.A.R. Labs went boom.
他和我擦肩而过
He walked right past me.
你知道斯泰因擅长转化领域
You see, Stein specialized in transmutation.
分子化变形
Molecular transmography.
量子拼接
Quantum splicing.
把两物合二为一
Taking two things and making them one.
我们来看录像带  好吗
Let's go to the videotape, shall we?
好  停
Okay, stop.
现在点几下放大
Now zoom in a few clicks.
快进  一帧一帧放
Now advance it, frame-by-frame.
他的眼睛
His eyes.
变成了白色  就像罗尼的一样
They turned white, just like Ronnie's.
现在暂停
Now, stop there.
在巨量能量中
In the mass of energy.
-看起来像  -罗尼
- Looks like-- - Ronnie.
和斯泰因教授
And Professor Stein.
暗物质把他们融为一体
The dark matter merged them together.
这就解释了为什么罗尼有些失去自我
Explains why Ronnie hasn't seemed quite himself lately.
因为他不是罗尼
It's because he's not.
他是马丁·斯泰因
He's Martin Stein.
你可不能说我没有信守承诺
You can't say I didn't keep up my end of the bargain.
我觉得咱们扯平了  斯蒂芬
I figure that makes us even Stephen.
再会了
Adios.
你好  能给我一杯水吗
Excuse me, could I get some water?
喂
Yo.
你好
Excuse me?
-真不理我吗  -巴里·艾伦先生
- For real? - Mr. Barry Allen!
快过来
Come on down!
-上台来  -我才不要
- Or up. - I'm not doing it.
上来跟我一起吧
Come up here with me.
给他们点颜色瞧瞧
Oh, come show 'em what you got.
来吧
Come on.
巴里  巴里
Barry! Barry!
巴里  巴里  巴里
Barry! Barry! Barry!
巴里  巴里  巴里  巴里
Barry! Barry! Barry! Barry!
快看他的步伐  太快了
Look at him go. He's so fast!
你知道我不擅长唱歌的
You know I'm not much of a singer.
而你也不太擅长喝酒...
And you're not much of a drinker.
我们会让这里嗨翻天的
We are gonna bring this place down.
好吧  乖
Okay, just... good girl.
做好准备
Get ready.
*夏日恋情  刺激尽兴*
*Summer lovin' Had me a blast*
*夏日心动  难以掌控*
*Summer lovin' Happened so fast*
*遇到狂热爱我的女孩*
*I met a girl crazy for me*
*遇到帅气逼人的男孩*
*I met a boy cute as can be*
*火热夏日  渐渐流逝*
*Summer days driftin' away*
*凉凉夏夜  引人流连*
*To uh-oh those summer nights*
不仅跑得快  唱歌还好听
You're fast and you can sing?
你有什么不会的
What can't you do?
很显然  我没法阻止你喝酒
Stop you from drinking, apparently.
我都不知道这是不是我的酒
I'm not even sure that was mine.
我要去趟洗手间
I have to go to the bathroom.
好吧
Okay.
我想结账
Can I close out my tab, please?
斯蒂威
Hey, Stevie.
帮我朋友把单免了吧
Can my friend here tap out?
当然可以  琳达
Sure thing, Linda.
谢谢你  琳达
Thank you, Linda.
不客气  巴里
You're welcome, Barry.
你怎么知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
巴里  巴里  巴里
Barry. Barry. Barry.
是啊
Yeah...
刚才出丑了
Sorry about us up there.
实在是...
That's...
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
那简直是我在这听过
No, that was some of the best singing that I've heard
最棒的歌声了
come from that stage.
我的耳朵十分享受
You definitely made my ears happy.
别担心
Don't worry.
谢谢
Thanks.
刚刚那是你的女朋友吗
So... was that your girlfriend up there?
不是
Oh...no, no.
她是我朋友
She's a friend.
好吧
Okay.
对了  你有没有听说过一款手机应用
Hey. Have you heard of this new phone app?
特别神奇
It's so cool.
你看  只要用你的手机
Check it out. You just touch someone's phone
触碰别人的手机
with your phone, and it automatically
就会自动下载联系人信息
downloads your contact info.
太厉害了
That is cool.
看到没  你有我手机号了
See? You have my number.
该怎么使用  就看你的了
What you do with it now is up to you.
好
Okay.
-巴里  -怎么
- Barry? - Yeah?
我感觉不太舒服
I don't feel good.
好  过来
Okay. Come on.
还好吗
Okay?
八万
80 grand.
我欠你的
What I owe.
现在两清了吧
So we square now?
差不多
Almost.
真牛逼
Holy crap.
你这么惊讶  我很开心
I'm glad you're impressed.
现在两清了吗
So we cool now?
绝对的
Absolutely.
清得不能再清了
Couldn't be cooler.
所以我们应该继续合作
Which is why I think we need to keep working together.
利用我的消息
With what I know,
和你们的本领
and what you can do,
我们携手  前途不可限量啊
We can be looking at a very lucrative future.
警察  所有人趴下
Police! Everybody down!
宝贝
Oh, baby!
别开枪
Hold it right there.
该死
Damn.
我们还在跑吗
Are we still running?
不  我们已经到了
No, we are here.
喝了伏特加还跑这么快
Vodka and super-speed--
似乎不是个好主意
not a good combination.
来吧
Come on.
你要打给她吗
So, are you gonna call her?
谁
Who?
那个女孩
That girl.
把电话号码给你的那个
The one who gave you her number.
其实我还没想过
I hadn't really thought about it.
你肯定想过
Yes, you have.
不过我了解你  你不会打的
But I know you. You won't.
你会让她从你的指间溜走
You'll let her slip right through your fingers
因为你觉得自己没资格幸福
because you think you don't deserve happiness.
但是你有所不知  你也需要被拯救
But what you don't realize is, you need a little saving, too.
帮帮我
Little help, please.
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
你又救了我
There you go again.
救我离开了那条邪恶的裙子
Saving me from that evil dress.
上床睡吧
Get in bed.
你有没有偷看
Did you sneak a peek?
偷看我的身材
At my goods?
我如果看了就不算英雄了
I wouldn't be much of a hero if I did.
好吧  不过你想看一眼也可以的
Yeah, but it's okay if you peeked a little.
你做了那么多好事  可以奖励你一下
You deserve a peek for all the good stuff you do.
多喝点水
Drink lots of water.
今晚谢谢你
Thank you for tonight.
我唱了歌
I sang.
不客气
Any time.
巴里
Hey, Barry?
能不能陪陪我  等我睡着再走
Will you stay with me until I fall asleep?
当然
Sure, yeah.
太大声了
So loud.
我只是想确认你没事
I just wanted to make sure you're okay.
不妨说我嫉妒你千杯不醉的能力吧
Let's just say I envy your inability to get drunk.
我不太记得昨晚的事了
I don't remember much from last night.
是啊  那再好不过了
Yeah, that's probably for the best.
夏日恋情
Summer loving.
天呐  这个我记得
Oh, God. That I do remember.
怎么了
What's wrong?
西斯科  有话跟你们说
Cisco...has something he needs to tell you.
哈特利不见了
Hartley's gone.
他从监狱管道逃出来了吗
He escaped from the Pipeline?
那怎么可能
How is that even possible?
我放他出来的
I let him out.
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
你戴着眼镜  我没法说
I can't tell with those glasses on.
我想大喊大叫  挥动双手
I'd like to yell and wave my arms,
但我怕我会吐
but I'm afraid I'd throw up.
为什么  你在想什么
Why? What were you thinking?
你知道他有多危险
You know how dangerous he is.
哈特利说他知道罗尼发生了什么事
Hartley said he knew what happened to Ronnie.
我跟你说过别查了
I told you to let it go.
我不想你为我调查这个
I didn't want you looking into that for me.
我不是为你
I wasn't doing it for you.
我
I...
在加速器爆炸前  我把罗尼关在里面
I sealed Ronnie into the accelerator before it blew.
他让我等两分钟
He told me to wait two minutes,
我等了  但他没有回来
and I waited, but he didn't come back.
我没法不去想
And I can't stop thinking,
如果我多等十几二十秒
10, 20 seconds and...
罗尼就不会变成他现在的样子
Ronnie wouldn't be like he is right now.
我很多次想告诉你
I've wanted to tell you so many times.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
所以一直以来你都守着这个秘密
So you carried that around this whole time?
如果罗尼在这  你知道他会说什么吗
Do you know what Ronnie would say if he was here?
他会说你做的没错
He would say that you did the right thing.
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
那晚发生的事不是任何人的错
What happened that night wasn't anybody's fault.
算了吧
Come on.
我们不是还要抓瞬移女吗
Don't we have a teleporter to catch?
我们确实有个瞬移女要抓
We do have a teleporter to catch.
幸运的是  我们得出了很棒的理论
And fortunately, we do have a promising theory.
看看这个
Take a look at this.
现在  这是肖娜留下的粒子
Now, this is the normal behavior
正常活动的状态
of the particulate that Shawna left behind.
看看当我们移除光线后会发生什么
Watch what happens when we remove light.
肖娜只有在看的到的情况下才能瞬息移动
Shawna can only become entangled with something she can see.
只要不让她看见
Take away her ability to do that--
她就不能瞬间移动了
She can't teleport.
没错
Exactly.
所以  我们只需把她带到黑暗的空间里
So, we just need to get her into a dark space.
我们要怎么做到这个
How do we do that?
问得很好
It's a valid question.
你好
Hello?
什么
What?
好  我马上去
Yeah, I'll be right there.
好
All right.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我爸爸
M-my dad.
他被人刺了
He's been stabbed.
爸爸  发生什么事了
Dad...what happened?
我只能说  那是非常严厉的警告
A rather stern reminder, I'd say,
别去搀和马克斯·斯德哥海默的事
not to poke around Marcus Stockheimer's business.
爸爸  我叫你停手了
Dad, I told you to stop.
你爸爸打给我说了更多的情报
Your dad called me with more intel.
帮助我们找到了克莱和肖娜
It helped us track down Clay and Shawna
并逮捕了斯德哥海默
and arrest Stockheimer.
我还成功地搞砸了马克斯最大的抢劫
I managed to screw up Marcus's big heist, too, so...
你们俩一直在合作  你却没告诉我
You two kept working together, and you didn't tell me?
不是他的错
It isn't his fault.
我是为了帮助你
I did it to help you.
你被刺受伤不是在帮助我
You getting stabbed and beaten is not helping me.
我  我在这
Look, I-I-I-I don't get to
感到自己没什么用
feel useful very much in here.
所以如果我能帮你改变一下
So if I can help you for a change,
我会想去帮助你的
I'm gonna want to be there for you.
就像这么多年来  你一直在我身边一样
Just like you've been there for me all these years.
是啊
Yep.
你说马克斯准备干一票大的抢劫
You said Marcus had a big heist coming up?
你知道其他相关的信息吗
Do you know anything else about it?
爸爸  告诉我是谁打伤的你
Dad, tell me who did this to you.
不  没关系的  猛男
No, it doesn't matter, slugger.
但你说你想帮我
But you said you want to help me.
那就帮我
So help me.
马克斯的一个手下
One of Marcus's boys.
朱利叶斯
Julius.
搞什么
What the hell?
晚上好  朱利叶斯
Evening, Julius.
我怎么出来的
How'd I get out here?
你越狱了
You escaped.
如果他们抓到我逃跑
They catch me trying to escape,
他们会给我加判五年的
they're gonna add five years to my sentence.
事实上  是十年
Ten, actually.
除非你告诉我
Unless you tell me where
马克斯下次要在哪动手
Marcus Stockheimer's next job is gonna be.
狱警随时可能到
Oh! Guards will be here any second.
是我就开始说了
I'd start blabbing.
好
Okay!
Okay.
是圣路易斯州联邦储备银行的
It's a TDK and money transfer truck
一辆运钞车
coming from the Federal Reserve Bank in St. Louis.
应该有几百万
Supposed to be millions.
运送时间大约在八点
Delivery around 8:00.
我知道就这么多  我发誓
That's all I know. I swear.
那就是现在
That's right now.
我怎么办
Hey, what about me?
我想有人跟踪我们
I think we got company.
搞什么
What the--
好了
Okay.
走吧
Let's go.
我来搞定他
I got this.
你为什么这么多管闲事
Why the hell do you care what we do?
你是警察还是别的什么人
Are you a cop or something?
我是别人
Something.
打倒他
Come on!
巴里  记住  如果她看不到就不能瞬移
Barry, remember: she cannot teleport if she cannot see.
限制她的视野
Limit her field of vision.
不
No.
他抛下了我
He left me.
她有办法从这里瞬移逃走吗
Is there any way she can teleport out of this?
不可能
It's impossible.
这是单向玻璃
It's one-way glass.
里面装有镜子
It's mirrored on the inside.
危险人物永远也不可能再次从这里逃离
No one dangerous is ever gonna get out of this thing again.
肖娜
Shawna.
克莱弃你而去
Clay left you.
他在外逍遥  而你却在这里
He's out there, and you're in here.
你知道疯狂的是什么吗
You know what the crazy thing is?
我还爱着他
I still love him.
西斯科
Cisco.
疯狂没有问题
Crazy is right.
有的人值得你为之疯狂
Some people are worth being crazy for.
抱歉  那晚我喝得太醉了
I'm sorry if I was a bit of a drunken mess the other night.
其实那晚还挺好玩的
Actually, it was pretty fun.
是的
Yeah, it was.
知道吗
You know what?
我想大家对你和我的看法没错
I think everybody's been right about you and me.
我们俩长期以来挂念着他人
Both of us have been hung up on people for way too long.
如果西斯科说得是真的
If what Cisco says is true,
罗尼和马丁·斯泰因合为一体
that Ronnie merged with Martin Stein,
那他就已经不在了
then he's not alive anymore.
我也该放下他了
Time for me to move on.
重新找一个令我为之疯狂的人
Find someone new to be crazy about.
好吧
All right, well.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
当然
Yes, sure.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
那是给你的
That's for you.
我想你也许能帮到我
I thought maybe you could help me out,
如果你愿意的话
if you're willing.
这份资料和铁山监狱的越狱事件有关
This is about the breakout at Iron Heights.
克莱·帕克  他仍然逍遥法外
Clay Parker. He's still on the loose,
我们要抓住他
and we need to catch him.
可你为什么把这个交给我
Why are you giving this to me?
因为你是个好记者
Cause you're a good reporter.
而我也只认识你
And the only one I know.
你不是唯一一个速度快的人
You're not the only one who's fast.
你来这做什么
Hey, what are you doing here?
如果你是来看我的
If you came to check on me,
那真的很贴心
that is really sweet,
但是我想一切都会顺利的
but I think everything's gonna be okay.
我很高兴
I'm glad.
其实我不是来看你的
I actually am not here to see you.
不是吗
No?
不是  我和人约好一起吃午饭
No, I have a lunch date.
和谁
With who?
-准备好了吗  -你来了
- Ready. - Hey.
你就是那位新来的特约记者吧
Oh, hey, you're our new stringer, right?
是的
Yeah.
我叫琳达·帕克  体育部的
I'm Linda Park. Sports.
我叫爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West.
你们俩是怎么认识的
How did you two meet?
这事说来有趣了
Well, it's actually kind of a funny story.
晚点告诉你吧
Yeah, I'll tell you later, all right?
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- You ready? - Yeah.
-好  -晚点见
- Okay. - See ya.
午饭吃得开心
Have fun.
这次是正式的约会吧
So an actual date this time.
不错啊
Good for you.
你没和她说你爸在蹲监狱吧
You didn't tell her your dad's in the slammer?
没  杂志上说那会倒人胃口
No, I read in a magazine that that's a big turnoff.
聪明
Smart.
看到这篇报道了吗
You see this?
没
No.
还没
I haven't.
闪电侠
The Flash.
我见过他一次
I saw him once.
就在这
In here.
看到他救了乔一命
Watched him save Joe's life.
乔和我说过
Joe told me about that.
看来他很幸运啊
I guess he was lucky.
幸运儿乔
Lucky Joe.
最奇怪的是
The strangest thing.
我被朱利叶斯殴打  最后被送到这里
I get roughed up by Julius, end up in here.
然后突然间  朱利叶斯因为想逃狱被抓
Next thing I know, Julius is caught trying to escape,
声称是闪电侠带他越狱的
claims the Flash broke him out.
看来很久都不会看到朱利叶斯了
Won't be seeing Julius for a long time now.
看来我也很幸运
Guess I'm lucky too?
老爸
Dad.
如果我是闪电侠
If I was the Flash,
你认为我不会第一时间告诉你吗
don't you think that you'd be the first to know about it?
如果我儿子是闪电侠  我会告诉他几件事
Well, if the Flash were my son, I'd tell him a few things.
首先  我会告诉他这个世界很危险
First off, I'd tell him it's a dangerous world,
所以要小心
so be careful.
然后再告诉他  他是个英雄
Then I'd tell him he's a hero.
他救了很多人
And he's saving a lot of lives.
但最重要的是我想让他知道
But the most important thing for him to know, I feel,
他的父亲为他感到骄傲
is that his father's proud of him.
这个区域的电力网一直出毛病
Power grid's been going haywire in this sector.
系统太旧了
The system's so antiquated.
那是什么声音
What was that?